Now in this lecture I'm going to show you a hands-on demo of the Amazon Bedrock Prom caching.
So what I have done is I have just written a Lambda function demo prompt caching.
And if you can just show you the code here, so what I have done is I have created some static
prefix or system prompt and it's just generic information that helps the foundation model
to get some context. So this is going to be reusable or cacheable. And then I said,
okay, cache point as type default. And then I have some dynamic user prompt. Again, I put
a lot of it as static. Now the only thing that is going to change here is the machine ID. So as a
change the value of the machine ID, I will ask it to summarize. So then we'll see what is the
reduction in the number of tokens. So basically, since this is static, we should see some reduction
in the number of tokens and also latency. Okay, so that's basically the function I have written.
Okay, now let's take a look. So I've already written a prompt caching test. So let me just quickly show
you. So you can see here, this is the machine ID. And right now it is 4522. So I will run it once.
So it will store the static part of the prompt. And then I will change the machine ID.
And basically, it will change this machine ID, but we'll still be able to reuse some part of the
static prompt. Okay, now let me just go ahead and invoke this. Let me just go ahead and say test.
Let me just click on this. Okay, now you can see here, basically latency is 1, 3, 4, 5 milliseconds.
And the number of total tokens used is we have the input token 143 and output token is 350.
So let me just copy this and we'll see the change. So let me just paste it here.
And now let me just go back to my lambda function. Okay, now I'm just going to change the machine
ID. So I'll just click on this. And let's say the machine ID is 99. And then I'll just do a save.
Okay, now this has been saved. Now let me just go ahead and test it again.
Okay, so it continues to run. Okay, I've waited a few seconds and now it has generated a response.
So you can see latency this time is 1074 seconds. If we just go to the previous request,
then latency was 1345. So it has reduced the latency. So now we are also able to see
this cache read input tokens. So it has reused 77 tokens. Obviously this was a very short prompt
that we had written. But if you're going to write longer prompts and the documents are going to be
much more large, there's going to be a lot of reusability. So I just wanted to quickly show you
how you can use prompt caching. Now you can also see this capability from the console itself.
So if I just go to this chat playground and let me just select a model, let me say no more pro.
And if I just scroll down here, you'll be able to see prompt caching. So I can enable this and
your prompts and model responses are automatically saved in cache checkpoint. But when
you try it through the console, sometimes it doesn't work. So that's why I showed it to you
programmatically. Okay, so that's pretty much it from this lecture. I'll see in the next lecture.
Thank you.